Contact

4252310081 (Home) conor.mcmillan@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ conormcmillan (LinkedIn) vimeo.com/128072264 (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Electrical Engineering
Troubleshooting
Computer-Aided Design (CAD)

Conor McMillan

Hardware Engineer

San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

As a kid I was constantly taking toys, tools and computers apart. I experienced my world though disassembly, building and hacking together something new. At school I was the engineer that took courses outside of my discipline; find myself in areas like theater, communications and electrical engineering. I found my passions in prototyping, robotics/automation and art.

I strive to be on leading edge. More often than not I find myself figuring out how to make a new product work or how to solve a new problem that no solution exits for.

Experience

Cruise

Senior Product Development Engineer December 2021 - Present (1 year 10 months)

Apple

Mechanical Electrial Engineer August 2018 - December 2021 (3 years 5 months)

The Select Group - Apple Hardware Design Engineer April 2018 - August 2018 (5 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Working within the iCloud organization

- -Taking complex systems from prototype to production with manufacturing partners and focusing on system lifecycle
- -system component and hardware qualification (e.g. environmental, performance, integrated test, reliability, etc.)
- -Responsible for electrical and mechanical design
- -Roadmap planning
- -Design verification based on contract manufactures.

WorldStage, Inc.

New Product Reserch and Devlopment Engineer February 2016 - April 2018 (2 years 3 months)

San Carlos, CA

WorldStage provides Audio, Video and Lighting technologies to the corporate, artistic and theatrical communities. The Inventions group has the express purpose of developing new consumer facing electronics including displays, control systems and LED products.

Custom Products

- ◆Android hardware development including AOSP and kernel development
- ◆Developed new products with vendors in South Korea, Taiwan and China.
- ◆Project management for new custom displays. Responsible for mechanical and electrical design oversight
- ◆IOT product development including web connected temperature sensor, power factor, voltage and current sensors
- ◆Rolled out custom software solutions for interactive, playback and management of display installs
- •Reverse engineering of electrical components to determine product lifecycle and performance under higher thermal loads
- ◆Designed motion based art installation using PLC and servo drives for installation work

Production Work

- ◆Lead a team of five on a three-week project spanning multiple sites, vendors and clients
- ◆Collaborated with technicians and vendors to create repair manuals and hardware setup guidelines
- ◆Performed engineering verification for long term install projects

Tekamaki

Mechanical and Design Engineering July 2015 - February 2016 (8 months)

San Carlos, CA

Tekamaki, a company focused on putting technology to work telling stories. As events have become more integrated it involves researching technology and spending time on preproduction.

- Developed product prototypes
- ◆Planed testing protocols for new devices
- Onsite hardware installation, troubleshooting and managemnt

- ◆Supported installation teams in CAD and pre vis work
- ◆Worked with onsite teams developing documentation for custom products
- Design, layout and manufacturing of trade show booth seen bellow

Self -Employed Freelance Event Tech September 2010 - July 2015 (4 years 11 months) Cheney, wa

- Collaborated with production teams at local community theater to provide support to sound operator
- ◆ Designed and installed 8.2 channel sound system at EWU theater.
- Provided support during budgeting, purchase and install to EWU Music
 Department with new sound board purchase, DAW and Computer purchase.
- Designed and budgeted video projection system for EWU Theater
- Worked with local artistic director to developed a long term growth plan for a new sound and video system
- Developed green initiatives working with grant team for long term financial savings

Eastern Washington University 6 years 3 months

Eagle Sound Technical Supervisor June 2012 - March 2015 (2 years 10 months) cheney, washington

Lead and manage Eagle sound production. A revenue generating student group that sets up for concerts, lectures, conferences. Providing a full range of multimedia solutions for student clubs, organizations and campus departments.

- Budgeted and implemented a budget purchase of \$60,000 for event equipment
- Coordinated approx. 980 events a year. Supervising and assigning student teams across campus to meet event production needs
- ◆ Trained staff on new equipment purchase; including BlackMagic video switchers, Allen Heath and X32 audio boards and GrandMa 2 lighting console

MARS Lab January 2009 - August 2012 (3 years 8 months) Cheney, Washington Multimedia Activities Resource Services (MARS) provided students, staff, and faculty access to high quality production facilities for the creation of multimedia for scholastic and personal use.

- Supported labs that operate Linux, OSX and Windows boot environment based on Apple hardware.
- Lead development of open source tools to maintain campus machines across platforms with campus lab teams
- Created training standards for new employs that assisted students.
- Helped students with projects across multimedia platforms in video, print and digital art

Goodrich

Program Engineering Intern July 2012 - December 2012 (6 months)

Spokane, Washington

- Reworked existing prototype equipment to aid in manufacturing.
- Designed and built machine safety equipment.
- Developed testing and reuse standards for parts saving approximately \$500,000 a year
- Worked with a student team developing machines to meet manufacturing needs
- Used SolidWorks to convert legacy drawings into current digital database
- Introduced prototype machines into production after production metrics were established
- ◆ Refined machine design to meet uptime of 24/7

Discovery Student Adventures Social Media Specialist May 2011 - November 2012 (1 year 7 months)

Airway Heights, Washington

- Worked with an international team to create new communication and marketing tools for traveling students
- Edited media and marketing materials as needed with day to day updates and edits
- Worked with marketing team to automate social media networks and keep them up to date

The Walt Disney Company Industrial Engineering Intern March 2010 - August 2010 (6 months)

Anaheim, california

Worked with Client and project-driven teams across Disney domestic Parks and Resorts.

- ◆ Developed flow models to accommodate 117,000 guests around resort
- Quantified service standards across resort call centers. Working with teams in both Flordia and Calforina
- Designed work time study tracking program and supervised the study to understand workforce tasks and time for each
- Created database statistic tools to quantify time study data assessing almost 300 man hours

Geek Squad

Counter Intelligence Agent 2007 April 2007 - June 2008 (1 year 3 months)

Interacted with customers on a daily basis where satisfaction is key. Utilized knowledge of individual customer needs to provide a complete solution.

- -Established guest interaction standards as well as metrics to gauge customer satisfaction
- -Created training practices for teaching new employees proper guidelines and standards
- -Developed collaborative tools to lower turn time to less then 72 hours

Education

Eastern Washington University
for Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering/Mechanical
Technology · (2008 - 2015)